# DEEPANSHU KUMAR SINGH

Birmingham, UK | Deepanshukumar787@gmail.com | +44 7448 943868

Portfolio <a href="https://deepanshusportfolio.my.canva.site/">https://deepanshusportfolio.my.canva.site/</a>

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/deepdks/

## PERSONAL PROFILE

Accomplished an MSc in Master's in Marketing and Strategy at Aston University with deep knowledge of integrating B2B strategies. A well-organised and creative individual with a keen interest in digital marketing and market research. Developing strong marketing skills through academic projects and practical knowledge. My technical skills include proficiency in HubSpot, SEO, and digital campaign management across CRM, email, website management, and social media platforms.

### **EDUCATION**

# Aston University MSc Marketing and Strategy

Birmingham, UK

Sept 2022 - Jun 2024

- Simulated company operations and gained an in-depth understanding of top management functions and decision-making processes.
- Engineered a new strategic framework by integrating Blue Ocean Strategy principles with innovative methodologies, aimed at enhancing HP's market share and competitive advantage.
- Researched and authored a thesis examining the instrumental function of microinfluencers in cultivating positive brand perceptions for new and emerging brands within the public domain.

# Delhi College of Arts and Commerce Bachelor of Commerce

Delhi, India

Jul 2018 – May 2021

- Acquired comprehensive insights into the internal workings and structural behaviour of companies through rigorous coursework and practical experiences.
- Developed and executed live advertisements, enhancing practical advertising skills and creative thinking.
- Established a vast professional network within the advertising industry and among fellow students and faculty.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

# Eagle Ways Marketing Digital Marketing Intern

London, UK

Jun 2023 - Jul 2023

- Created over 100 posts for clients and Eagle Ways to increase engagement during my internship.
- Assisted over 50 clients by using social media ads (Instagram and Facebook), managing multiple social media handles, and creating posts and visually appealing ads.
- Helped in SEO and website building with backlinks and Google Analytics and gave content for the website.

Fitkilter Delhi, India

# Social Media and PR Manager

Dec 2021 - Jul 2022

- Acquired 10+ clients and generated 50+ leads through strategic outreach and marketing campaigns.
- Created over 50 posts including both pictures and videos, boosted the brand's visibility by multiple of times.
- Gathered and analysed customer feedback through videos, emails, and social media interactions to improve service offerings.

# Ludhiana Greentop Creative Content Designer

Delhi, India

Jan 2021 - Aug 2021

- Created 20+ videos for social media using Adobe Premiere Pro and content provided by the ground team.
- Provided 10+ leads through market research and cold calling that converted into sales to the Finance team for funds.
- Increased digital campaign ROI by 30% through optimized strategies.

#### RELATED EXPERIENCES

Adroit DCAC Delhi, India
Secretary Sept 2018 – May 2021

- Increased engagement and presence of the society as a content creator, achieving a 30% increase in interactions within 2 months.
- Secured sponsors and collaborations worth up to ₹150,000 funds for the society.
- Handled recruitment drive for over 2 years, interviewing over 250 people.

Enactus DCAC Delhi, India

## **Social Media and Operations Manager**

Dec 2018 - May 2021

- Created over 50 Flyers and posters through Adobe Photoshop and Express to promote social events and gatherings.
- Worked as a photographer and editor to make impactful stories that helped in the national competition.
- Supervised ground team to create awareness for the projects the society leads.

#### OTHER EXPERIENCES

WingStop, Birmingham – Team Member (Oct 2023 – Present)

Constellation – Hospitality Services (Jul 2023 – Feb 2024)

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HubSpot, SEO Marketing, Digital Campaign Management, CRM, Social Media Management, Google Analytics, Marketing Automation, Adobe Suite (Premiere Pro, Photoshop, Lightroom, After Effects), Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, Branding and Marketing Techniques, Influencer Marketing, Strategic Marketing, Content Marketing, Photo and Video Skills, Market Research, Logo Design, WordPress.

## **AWARDS**

- Best Designer award in Advertising Society
- Winner of a photography competition in college
- Volunteer at Win Over Cancer NGO
- Best Graphic Design Intern at Ludhiana Greentop
- Volunteer at Sambhav NGO

#### **HOBBIES**

- Photography: Visiting various places to take pictures, connecting with nature.
- Technology Enthusiast: Interested in AI, cars and the latest tech innovations.
- Content creation: Creating reels and edits about different themes.

## **PROJECTS**

#### Thesis:

https://drive.google.com/file/d/1B1od4GMshEbiQnZSMw1027a4veWrkwt/view?usp=sharing

## Internet of Things:

https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1-pmez8fZxNbNHeeutaHGqo7LK2y-SNS\_?usp=drive\_link